在我们文明之初 流传着一个传说
There's a legend that precedes the dawn of our civilization.
那是一个非常巨大 非常强大...
A vile god, so large and so powerful
以吞噬行星为能量的邪恶之神
that it consumed entire planets as fuel.
没人相信这传说是真的
Few believed such a thing could be true,
直到有一天我们亲眼看到了宇宙大帝
until the day we saw Unicron with our own eyes.
但他不是冲着我们的星球而来
But he didn't just come for our planet.
他想要的是我们最前沿的技术
He wanted our greatest technology,
曲速钥匙
the Transwarp Key.
他派了他最得力的手下去寻找
And he sent his most powerful henchman to collect it,
天灾
Scourge.
越来越多的敌人来了
More enemies are landing.
这里马上就会有危险了
We won't be safe for long.
钥匙还在我们这里么?
Do we have the key?
你必须拿着钥匙
You must take it.
把它藏起来
Keep it hidden,
不要落入宇宙大帝之手
so that it never falls into the hands of Unicron.
圣猿 我们还可以战斗
But, Apelinq, we can fight.
不 保护曲速钥匙才是最重要的
No. Protecting our Transwarp Key is all that matters!
走 用它离开这里
Go. Use it to escape.
你呢?
What will you do?
我来拖住他
I'll hold him off.
给你们赢得些时间
Buy you some time.
那我和你在一起战斗
Then I'm staying with you.
这是我的战斗
This is my fight.
听着 如果宇宙大帝拿到了钥匙
Listen, if Unicron were to get the key,
它就能打开穿越时空的传送门
he could open a portal through time and space
整个宇宙的毁灭将没有尽头
with no end to the worlds he could destroy.
现在是时候你来领导巨无霸了
It is now your time to lead the Maximals,
擎天圣
Optimus Primal.
你就是这个星球上最厉害的战士
So you're this planet's great warrior.
你们的世界真漂亮
You have such a beautiful world
生机勃勃
filled with an abundance of life.
香甜可口
Savory.
我的主人饿了
My master grows hungry.
把曲速钥匙给我 他会放一条生路给你们
Give me the Transwarp Key, and he will spare your home.
我们宁愿毁灭 也不让他去祸害其他星球
We'd rather die than let him reach other planets.
那我就成全你吧
So be it.
服侍伟大的宇宙大帝的好处
Benefits of serving the almighty Unicron.
他们永远学不会
They never learn.
太迟了 天灾
You're too late, Scourge.
你的主人将永远被困在这个星系
Your master will be trapped in this galaxy forever.
不!
No!
他的牺牲将是我们的誓约
His sacrifice will be our oath.
保护钥匙
To preserve the key,
不计代价
no matter the cost.
你让他们带着曲速钥匙跑了
You let them slip away with the Transwarp Key.
搜遍整个宇宙 找出巨无霸
Scour the universe and find where the Maximals have gone.
你拿到钥匙后 用钥匙带我去你那里
When you acquire the key, use it to bring me to you.
是 大人
Yes, my lord.
钥匙在手 唯吾独尊
Once I have the key, I alone will reign supreme.
《变形金刚6：超能勇士崛起》
∮ 在这里二对五 宝贝儿 ∮
∮ It's two against five here, baby ∮
∮ 加油 二对五 ∮
∮ Come on, two against five ∮
∮ 一路上遇到的对手都是垃圾 ∮
∮ The opponents we've met along the way have been garbage ∮
∮ 现金支配着我周围的一切 ∮
∮ Cash dictates everything around me ∮
∮ C.R.E.A.M. 得到什么... 是的 ∮
∮ C.R.E.A.M. gets what... Yes, it does ∮
∮ 看看这个老苍蝇 ∮
∮ Look at this old fly ∮
∮ 没错 ∮
∮ rest assured ∮
∮ 现金支配着我周围的一切 ∮
∮ Cash dictates everything around me ∮
∮ C.R.E.A.M. 揣着钱 ∮
∮ C.R.E.A.M. Taking the money ∮
∮ 美元钞票 伙计们 ∮
∮ Dollar bills, guys ∮
∮ 我在犯罪的边缘长大 活跃在《纽约时报》的版面 ∮
∮ I grew up on the edge of crime, in the pages of the New York Times ∮
∮ 妈妈对老爸大发雷霆 ∮
∮ Mom's mad at Dad ∮
∮ 于是我们搬到了少林寺 ∮
∮ So we moved to Shaolin Temple ∮
∮ 一位年轻的小伙子 摇晃着金饰品 ∮
∮ A young man shaking his gold jewelry ∮
∮ 傻瓜 只有这样 我才能离开.. ∮
∮ Fool, it's the only way I can leave.. ∮
好了 宝贝 试试
All right, baby, come on.
让我换到钱 让我换到钱
Show me the money. Show me the money.
来了 好了
Here we go. There we go.
哟 刺猬 早餐准备好了吗?
Yo, Sonic. Breakfast ready yet?
我可不是你的管家 克里斯
I ain't your butler, Kris.
拜托 伙计 别说真名
Come on, man. No names over the airwaves.
小狐狸
It's Tails.
哦 抱歉
Oh, my bad,
布鲁克林 威尔逊大道974号 2-C公寓
Kristopher Diaz from 974 Wilson Avenue,
克里斯托弗·迪亚兹
Apartment 2-C, Brooklyn.
别说真名 有监听
No real names. They're listening.
没有政府秘密机构监听我们 小狐狸
Ain't no secret government agencies worried about us, Tails.
趁早餐热着 你赶紧过来
Now get your behind out here while it's hot.
至少他们是这么做的 我给你熨好了
At least they got that going for 'em. Here, I ironed this for you.
- 我已经熨过了 - 什么…就像你煎鸡蛋一样?
I already ironed it. What... Like you cooked those eggs?
什么意思嘛?  这是…调过味的煎蛋
What you mean? They're just... seasoned.
拉到吧
Aw, come on.
来吃吧 兄弟
Come eat, bro.
我过不了库巴大魔王这关
I can't get past Bowser.
好吧 你也早上好
Well, good morning to you too.
把这个喝了 然后吃药
Drink this and take your medicine.
喝光 好么
All of it. Okay.
你确定可以带他去?
Are you sure you can take him?
是啊 去医院嘛 我有时间
Yeah, uh, hospital's on the way. I got time.
如果那位女主管在的话
And, if that lady, that administrator, is there
她要是给你医疗账单
and she mentions a bill,
你就…
just...
告诉她我们正在想办法
tell her we're handling it.
我会的 到了明天 我就能帮忙了
I will. And after today, I'll be able to help out more.
祝你面试顺利
Good luck on the interview.
别忘记他们讲笑话时要笑
Don't forget to laugh at all their jokes.
白人都那尿性 妈妈 注意言辞
White people love that shit. Ma, language.
好的 记住 我今晚有课 所以我会晚点回家
Okay!  Remember, I have class tonight, so I'll be home late.
-爱你们 -爱你
Los quiero. I love you.
快点 伙计 我们得进城一趟
Hurry up, man. We gotta get into the city.
嘿 等一下 等一下
Hey. Hold up. Hold up.
你的手又疼了?
Your hand's hurting again?
不 没什么
No, it's nothing.
让我看看
Yo, let me see.
克里斯
Kris.
都肿了
It's swollen.
镰状细胞肯定又阻塞了血液流动
The sickle cells must be blocking the blood flow again.
这情况有多久了?
How long has this been going on?
有几天了
Couple days.
听着 我们说过的
Hey, yo, look, I told you,
你得告诉我你不舒服
you gotta tell me these things.
你一个人战斗 还是我们一起战斗?
You fighting this alone, or we fighting it together?
我们一起
Together.
主队?
Home team?
主队
Home team.
十元两张 十元……不要碰任何东西
Two for ten. Two for... Stop touching everything.
哦 见鬼 不 克里斯 我怎么跟你说的
Oh, hell, no. Kris, what'd I tell you
让你的弟弟从婴儿床里走出来 怎么看起来挺二的?
about letting your mans come out the crib looking like a whole square?
我能做的就这么多
Only so much I can do.
随便吧 兄弟 看 给你
Yeah, whatever, bro. Look. Here.
噢! 我的狗!
Ooh! My dawg!
你什么时候才能让我充分发挥你的才华 给你换点真金白银?
When you gonna let me put your skills to work and get you some real money?
是啊 一个连有线电视都买不起的人说这话
Yeah. Says the dude who can't even afford cable.
“说这话……”
"Says the guy who..."
我不购买有线电视
I choose not to purchase cable.
是用我自己的方式抗议有线电视现代资本主义的
It's my own personal way to protest the vampiric nature
吸血鬼本性!
of modern-day capitalism!
祝你穿着满是灰尘的西装面试顺利!
Hey, good luck with that interview in that dusty suit!
啊啊 我来啦
Ugh! I'm coming.
嘿 朋友们 这个很不错
Hey, guys. That's a good one,
甲龙是一种有甲的恐龙
but the Ankylosaurus was an armored dinosaur.
谢谢 谢谢...感谢你们的耐心
Thank you, thank you... ...for being patient.
实习生?  实习生?
Intern? Intern?
我呼了你三次 你为什么不回电给我?
I paged you three times. Why didn't you call me?
因为如果我停下来给你回电的话，那就会迟到
Okay, well, I figured if I stopped to call, that would make me later.
警察在我们这
The police are here.
他们叫停了我们的艺术品拍卖会
They busted an art auction.
卖家称所有艺术品均是货真价实
The owner claims that everything is authentic,
但警察似乎不那么认为
but they want a second opinion.
好吧
All right.
达芬奇的素描是真的
The da Vinci sketch is legit.
这幅画是赝品
The painting's a copy.
真品在伦敦国家美术馆
Real one's at the National Gallery in London.
罗马花瓶
Roman vase.
这件有点价值 但这些佣金不能让你提早退休
Valuable, but you are not gonna retire off of them.
这个希腊咒语石板 这个真的会很贵
This Greek curse tablet, it would be expensive,
可惜是假的
but it's a fake.
你是怎么知道的?
How can you tell?
看到那文字了吗?  那是罗马字体
See the spelling? Roman.
在那个年代根本不存在
Doesn't even show up in that era.
懂了
Got it.
警官们 我知道了 所以…
Officers, I figured it out. So...
达芬奇的画是真的
The da Vinci, that is real.
你来自哪里?
Now, where did you come from?
你是何物?
What are you?
-那很美 是吧? -对
It's pretty neat, right? Yes.
它来自哪里?
Where is it from?
在苏丹刚被发现
They just discovered it in Sudan.
说是荷鲁斯时期 公元前五千年 努比亚人?
The boys say it's Horus, fifth millennia BC, Nubian?
这个符号可绝对不是象形文字
This symbol is definitely not hieroglyphic.
如果真像看起来那么奇特
Well, if it's as exotic as it looks,
我要上谷歌AI了
I'm gonna get a feature in Minerva.
呃 吉利安?
Uh, Jillian?
好了 朋友们 开始吧
Okay, team, let's do it.
规则是什么?
Okay, what are the rules?
兄弟如手足 女人如衣服
Bros before hos.
“别成麻烦
"Don't be a problem.
别找麻烦 ”
Don't go looking for a problem."
不然 我们就…会有麻烦
Or else we're gonna... Have a problem.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
好的 我一会儿就回来
Okay, I'll be back in a little bit.
迪亚兹先生吗?
Mr. Diaz?
我知道我们的账单付晚了
Hey, I know we're a little behind on the bill.
三个月了 在你的账户结清之前 你不能再带你弟弟来
Three months behind. Until your account is current, you can't bring your brother.
我说了 我会付清账单的
I've told you that. I'm gonna fix it.
只是还需要一点时间 可以先去急诊室
I need a little more time. Take him to the ER.
除非病情危重 否则他不能再去急诊室了
Well, they won't see him in the ER unless he's critical.
迪亚兹 他只有11岁 !
Mr. Diaz. He's 11!
11岁
He's 11 years old.
快点 克里斯 我们得走了
Come on, Kris, we gotta go.
-发生什么事了? -我一会儿告诉你 伙计 好吧?
- What happened? - I'll tell you later, man. All right?
来吧 我们离开这里吧
Come on. Let's get out of here.
嘿 坐在这里
Hey, yo. Sit here.
不要动!
And don't move!
需要帮忙吗? 是的
Can I help you? Yes.
我和安全主管毕夏普先生约了面试
Hey, I'm here for an interview with the head of security, Mr. Bishop.
我是诺亚·迪亚兹
I'm Noah Diaz.
面试取消了 不 不 肯定是搞错了
It's been canceled. No. No, that has to be a mistake.
是毕夏普先生吩咐的
Came right from Mr. Bishop.
只需要您的签字…
Just need your authorization...
毕夏普先生! 嘿!嘿!
Mr. Bishop! Hey! Hey!
没事的 沃克
It's okay, Walker.
是我 诺亚·迪亚兹先生 我觉得你的人可能弄错了
It's me, Noah Diaz. Sir, I think your boy back there is confused.
他说我们的面试取消了 是的
He said our interview was canceled. Because it is.
等等 为什么? 是您在电话里说我很适合这份工作
Wait, why? On the phone you said I was perfect for the job.
您说这只是个形式
You said this was just a formality.
在你的老领导给我通电话前确实是的
It was until your old commanding officer called me back.
他说你很勇敢 很专业 但不可靠
Said you were brave, an expert comtech, but unreliable.
无法信任你
Couldn't trust you.
你总是心不在焉
Your head was always somewhere else.
先生 我可以解释这一切
Sir, I can explain all of that.
我在家里有一些情况 我弟弟 他病了……
I had some responsibilities at home. My brother, he's sick...
你是为美国军队服务
You had a responsibility to the United States Army.
毕夏普先生! 先生
Mr. Bishop! Sir.
我工作很努力 真的? 我只是…
I'm a hard worker, okay? I just...
只是需要休息一下
I just really need a break.
听着 我不能让你这样的人毁了我在这里的一切
Listen, I can't have someone like you mess up what I've built.
像我这样的人?
Someone like me?
您根本不了解我!
You don't know anything about me!
我看得出你不懂团队协作
I know you don't know how to be part of a team.
天呐
God.
嘿 听着
Hey, look.
超人在他得到星球日报的工作之前
Superman went on a bunch of interviews
也参加了很多面试
before he got his job on the Daily Planet.
-但他从未放弃 -可我不是超人 克里斯
But he never gave up. I'm not Superman, Kris.
生活可不是漫画书
Life ain't a comic book.
我只是说一下 你会有下一次面试的
I'm just saying. You'll get the next one.
没有下一次了
Yo, there is no next one.
没人会来救我们 我们就有我们自己
No one's coming to save us. We're alone in this.
伙计 抱歉
Yo, man, I'm sorry.
没关系的
It's all right.
不 不是的
No, it's not.
这些都不是
None of this is.
你知道吗?
You know what?
来吧
Come on.
嘿 给你 兄弟
Yo, here, bro.
上楼去吧 我马上就来 好吗?
Just head upstairs. I'll be right there, all right?
你之前和我说发挥技能是指什么?
So what was you talking about earlier?
嘿 你想要一个吗?
Hey, yo, you want one?
不 我不需要糖果
No. I don't want any candy.
你得放轻松 伙计
You gotta relax, man.
你的负压影响了我的气场
Your energy is really affecting my chi.
我懂 我第一次也很紧张
And I get it. I was nervous my first time too.
但你可以做一些呼吸练习 或者别的什么 看着我
But you might want to do some breathing exercises, or something. Look at me.
伙计 伙计
My man, my man, my man, my man.
只是我以前没做过这种事
It's just I ain't done this before.
我知道 但是有钱的主就在那
I know that. But them rich cats in there,
他们每年向慈善机构捐赠大量钞票
they give a ton of paper to charities every year
就是为了让他们自我感觉好一些
to make themselves feel better.
如果你长远来看 我们是在帮他们
If you look at it from a holistic perspective, we doing them a favor.
嘿  你! 不客气!你能停下来吗?
Hey, yo! You're welcome! Will you stop?
-你在干什么? -这根本不会影响到他们的钱包
- What are you doing? - This ain't about to affect they pockets at all.
这将会非常简单
And it's about to be easy as hell.
那你为什么不亲自去做呢?
So why you ain't the one going in there and doing it?
小宝贝 因为我才是幕后策划
Because, papito, I'm the mastermind.
来吧 把这个塞进耳朵里
Now come on, put this in your ear.
伙计 你认真的吗? 这干净吗?
My man, you serious? Yo, is that even clean?
现在是第四节比赛 场上还剩最后十秒
It's the fourth quarter, we got about ten seconds left on the clock,
你手握最后一击的那个球
and you got the rock.
-把这个扔掉 -嘿 伙计!
- Get rid of this. - Hey, man!
不要猛摔门……
Don't slam the...
我去参会募捐晚宴了
Okay. I am off to my fundraiser.
-你觉得怎么样? -很好
- What do you think? - It's nice.
嗯 我能…我能跟你说点事吗?
Um, can I... Can I run something by you?
我做了一些研究
So I've been doing some research,
我不认为雕像是荷鲁斯时期的
and I don't think that the statuette is Horus.
事实上 它肯定不是
As a matter of fact, I'm sure it's not.
那些人认为它应该是大约在公元前5000年 对吧?
The boys dated it around 5000 BC, right?
但是努比亚人
But the Nubians,
在公元600年前
they never even had contact with the Egyptians
从未与埃及人接触过
until 600 years after that.
这些符号显然不是象形文字
The symbol's not hieroglyphic.
我认为符号不属于那个世界
I don't even think it's from that part of the world.
可能是阿兹特克人或印加人的
I think it might be Aztec or Inca.
并不是什么埃及神 应该是别的什么文明
It's not some Egyptian god. It's something else.
有点意思
Interesting.
帮我熨一下 好吗?
Get those pressed, okay?
好的吧
Yeah.
对了 深呼吸
There you go. Let that breath fill you up.
吸气…吐气
In... out.
别说了
Please stop talking.
好吧 好的 你不喜欢聊天
Okay, all right, I get it, you don't like to chitchat back and forth.
但我有东西要给你
But I got something for you.
盗版混音带?
You got a robbing mixtape?
哦 不
Uh, no.
放松音带
I got a liberating mixtape.
你感觉到了吗?
You feeling that, huh?
是的 随便吧
Yeah, whatever.
好吧 你所在的这部分楼栋应该没人
All right, there shouldn't be nobody in this part of the building.
你应该可以大摇大摆地进去
You should be able to just waltz right on in.
离大谱 这里全是人
Strike one, mastermind. This place is packed.
嘿 那就将错就错
Hey, well, to error is divine.
把它当成你的地盘
Just act like you own the place.
嘿 怎么了 兄弟? 很高兴再次见到你
Hey, wassup, brother? Good to see you again.
别显得可疑
Try not to look suspicious.
给你 给你 对不起 对不起 是你 兄弟
Here you go. Here you go. Sorry. Sorry. That's you, bro.
-眼镜不错 -我不知道…… -不知道你还戴眼镜
- Nice glasses. - I didn't know... - I didn't know you had glasses.
-你在干什么啊 -交朋友?
What are you doing, making friends?
-一切都好吗? -进来了
Everything good? We're in the mix.
嘿 让我看看你到底是什么
Hey. Let's see what you really are.
∮ 微风吹拂车身非常惬意 ∮
∮ We, like the breeze Flow straight out of our lids ∮
∮ 布鲁克林孩子摇滚致敬 ∮
∮ Them, they got moved By these hard-rock Brooklyn Kids ∮
∮ 跟着节奏一起躁动不停 ∮
∮ Us, floor rush when the DJ,s booming classics ∮
∮ 嘻哈音乐榜上赫赫有名 ∮
∮ You dig the crew on The fattest hip-hop record ∮
我的朋友说它就存放在后面
Now, my man said it's tucked in the back.
放了好几个星期了
Been there a couple weeks.
是一辆灰色的车
It's like a grayish car
带着…
with like a...
蓝色的条纹
Blue stripe.
好了 就像瑞克哥哥教你的那样
All right, now just like brother Reek showed you.
从窗户那里伸进去……
Down the window...
…轻轻扭动……
...a little wiggle...
…感受一下那个阻尼……
...feel that snag and...
…对了
...yeah.
现在我们就赚大钱了
Now we making money.
好吧 跟我说话啊啊 伙计
All right. Talk to me, homey.
我到车里了
I'm in.
这一点也不会疼
This won't hurt a bit.
停 停
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
我要失业了
I'm gonna lose my job.
我要进监狱了
I'm gonna go to jail.
这绝不是努比亚文明
It's definitely not Nubian.
这不可能
This cannot be.
呼叫所有汽车人! 呼叫所有汽车人!
Calling all Autobots! Calling all Autobots!
走你 混...
Yippee-ki-yay, mother...
擎天柱 我是阿尔茜 我看到一个景象
Prime, this is Arcee. I have a visual.
我看到的是什么?
What am I looking at?
回家的路
A way home.
呼叫所有汽车人!
Calling all Autobots!
我在做什么? 这里已经安全了
What am I doing? Well, the coast is clear out here,
你把车开出来的时候 这里没问题
so whenever you want to slide that thing on out, you good.
我做不到 我不做不到
I can't. I can't.
你不会开手动挡?
Like you can't drive stick or something?
不 只是…我不是小偷
No, it's just... I ain't no thief.
你现在有存在危机吗?
Are you having an existential crisis now?
我给你扭扭糖的之后就不该发生了
The deadline for that was when I offered you Twizzlers.
这是紧急情况
This is an emergency.
你能听到我吗 幻影? 出发了!
Can you hear me, Mirage? Roll out!
谁特么在那里说话?
Who the hell was that?
收音机 伙计 这车有毛病 我要出去
That's the radio, bro. This car is buggin'. I'm out.
我靠!
Shit!
-我靠 -嘿 你!
Oh, shit. Hey, you!
从车里出来!
Get out of the car!
我试着出来! 车是自己发动的 我保证!
I'm trying! The car started by itself, I promise!
看 不管用! 马上出去!
Look, it's not working! Get out now!
不! 等等! 你在干什么?
No! Wait! What you doing?
诺亚 怎么了……
Noah, what's...
瑞克! 瑞克!
Reek! Reek! Reek!
这可是秀级的表演!
Now, that's top-tier manifestation!
嘿 这车自己开了!
Yo, the car's driving by itself!
诺亚 你还好吗?
Noah, you good?
我不知道发生了什么!
I don't know what's going on!
它停不下来!
It won't stop!
停! 停! 你为什么不听指挥?
Yo, stop! Stop! Why aren't you listening?
你最好开慢点 不是我在开 是车自己在开!
You might wanna slow down. It's not me, it's the car!
-它发疯了! -不 不
It's possessed! No, no, no.
你只是肾上腺素过高了
You're just on an adrenaline high.
让我们做一些呼吸练习
Let's do some of them breathing exercises.
我不需要呼吸练习!
Yo, I don't need no breathing exercises!
这车在自动驾驶!
The car's driving by itself!
哦 巧了
Oh, snap.
瑞克 我们该怎么办?
Yo, Reek, what do we do?
诺亚 我听不见
Noah, I cannot hear you.
瑞克! 诺亚 我不能…
Reek! Noah, I can't...
不 他没有! 不 他没有离开我!
No, he did not! No, he did not just leave me!
-靠边! -救命!
Pull over! Help me!
哦! 你还好吗……
Oh! Are you ok...
开车 开车 开车
Drive. Drive, drive, drive, drive, drive!
桥 桥 桥……
The bridge. The bridge, the bridge...
去威廉斯堡!
Take the Williamsburg!
这里有一起10-37案件 银色保时捷
I got a 10-37 in progress. Silver Porsche.
不是吧 伙计?
You serious, man?
拜托 做点什么!
Hell, do something, please!
哟 不 不
Yo, nah. Nah, nah, nah.
洞幺 洞幺
Come in, come in.
-你能听到吗 幻影? -幻什么?
Can you hear me, Mirage? Mir-what?
哦 幻觉
Oh, Mirage.
哟 哟 慢点! 慢点!
Yo, yo, yo, slow down! Slow down!
感觉好极了!
That felt good!
-给力啊 你懂的 -该死的
Get some oil pumping, you know? Damn!
我闭关很久了 伙计
I've been cooped up forever, dude.
我都忘记有多久了
I can't tell you how old it gets!
幻影 藏起来
"Mirage, stay hidden.
幻影 别让人注意到你
Mirage, don't draw any attention to yourself.
幻影 《长大》只是一部电影 你永远不会成为那个男孩 ”
Mirage, Big is just a movie. You'll never be a real boy."
但那很有趣 伙计 你真有趣 伙计
But that was fun, man. You're fun, dude.
哦  对了 对你来说信息量太大了吧?
Oh, right. This is probably a lot for you, huh?
-后退! -嘿 怎么啦?
Back up! Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa. What's with the aggression?
我以为飙完车 我们就是兄弟了
I thought after the car chase, we were boys.
-你打算打我? -也许吧
Are you gonna hit me? Maybe.
这样吗?
It's like that?
嗯 硬汉
Hmm. Tough guy.
我喜欢这样 我非常喜欢
I like that. I like it a lot.
你是什么鬼?
What are you?
是被附身的车什么的么?
Some sort of possessed car or something?
不 那是骗人的啦 伙计
Nah. That's not real, man.
我是外星人
I'm an alien.
就像……就像E.T.吗?
Like... Like E.T.?
E.T? 待车篮子里那个丑八怪?
E.T.? The little ugly guy in the basket?
看看我这张帅气的脸庞! 我的名字叫幻影
Look at this face! The name's Mirage.
来吧 来一下 来一下
Come on. Give me a little, give me a little.
来一下啊 轻轻敲一下
Give me a little. Give a little tap.
轻轻敲我一下
Give me a little tap.
好了 现在我们是朋友了!
There you go. Now we're friends!
-哦 太棒了 -他们来了
Oh, great. The gang's here.
还有更多像你一样的? 一样的? 不
There are more like you? Like me? Nah.
冷静 他们才不会把你吓到
But be cool so they don't crush you.
啥？ 如果我是你 我会把管子放下
What? Yeah, I'd put that pipe down if I were you.
好吧 好吧 谁来了?
Well, well, who have we got here?
幻影 你做了什么?
Mirage, what have you done?
你把人类带到这里了?
You brought a human here?
擎天柱!  嘿! 看起来不错啊 伙计!
Optimus! Hey! Looking good, man!
等一下 那些是新的轮辋吗?
Wait a second. Are those new rims?
让你藏起来
You were told to stay hidden.
对的 对的 就是那么巧
Right, right. Crazy coincidence.
你在像擎天柱一样说…
When you called, all Optimus-like...
“汽车人 出发!”
"Autobots, roll out!"...
…这家伙已经在车里了
...this guy was already in the car.
但他真的很酷 很酷 酷么?
But he's cool, so it's cool. Cool?
不酷
Not cool.
你是谁 人类?
Who are you, human?
我谁都不是 我什么都没看见
I'm nobody. I ain't even seen nothing.
我现在什么都没看到
I'm not even seeing anything right now.
阿尔茜
Arcee.
二等兵诺亚·迪亚兹 美国陆军
Private Noah Diaz, US Army.
多次被嘉奖 一个懂电子的老法师
Multiple commendations. A wizard with electronics.
他是一名士兵
Huh. He's a soldier.
他看起来不像个士兵
He does not look like a soldier.
我觉得你看起来也挺大老粗的
I mean, you looking pretty rough yourself.
对不起 先生
Sorry, sir.
我晚一点再处理你的错误
I will deal with your mistake later.
我们感觉到的能量波动在4000千赫兹范围内
Okay, the energy surge we felt was in the 4,000 yottahertz range,
这是人类无法察觉的
which is undetectable to humans.
我从能量回声中重建了信号源
I've reconstructed the source from the energy echoes.
我简直不敢相信 它存在 它就在这里
I cannot believe it. It exists and it is here.
我到底在看什么?
What the hell am I looking at?
曲速钥匙
The Transwarp Key.
它被认为在几千年前就消失了
It was thought to be lost thousands of years ago.
曾经被用来打开时空传送门
It was once used to open space-time portals
到宇宙中能量块蕴含丰富的行星
to Energon-rich planets throughout the universe.
你是说能量块丰富的行星 比如……
You mean Energon-rich planets like...
塞伯坦
Cybertron.
地球上滞留了七年之后
After seven long years stranded on Earth,
我们终于找到回家的路了
we've finally found a way home.
等我抓到你 瑞克
Wait till I catch you, Reek.
好吧 那么这个曲... 曲速在哪里?
Okay, so where is this t-tran, t-trun...
曲速钥匙？ 谢谢你！
Transwarp Key? Thank you.
它在埃利斯岛新建的博物馆里
It's in the new museum on Ellis Island.
我们把博物馆炸了 然后拿走它!
Let's blow it up and get the hell out of Dodge!
不 我们不能就这么冲进去把它拿走 大黄蜂
No, we can't just go in blasting and steal it, Bee.
人类会追杀我们的
The humans will hunt us down.
我们需要的是悄无声息地进去
What we need is a quiet way in.
哦 让他去怎么样?
Ooh, how about him?
不 怎么啦？ 拜托 伙计
No. What? Come on, man.
他可以从其中一扇小门溜进去
He could slip in right through one of them little doors,
拿起钥匙 留张漂亮的借条 然后安全离开
grab the key, leave a nice IOU and peace out.
他是完美选择 怎么啦？
He's perfect. What?
不 这是个坏主意
No, it is a bad idea.
我同意老大的观点
I agree with Big Man.
所以 这是真的 各位 但是…
So, it's been real, y'all. But...
呃  暂停 幻影
Uh, time-out. Mirage.
我知道 我知道 放松 让我跟我的朋友说几句
I know. I know. Just relax. Let me just talk to my guy real quick.
别把我丢给这些混蛋 兄弟 我们是一个伟大的团队
Yo, don't leave me with these tight-asses, bro. We make a great team.
这是浪费时间
This is a waste of time.
听着 我不会为了太空机器人去闯博物馆的
Look, I'm not breaking into a museum for some space robots.
那友谊呢?
But what about for friendship?
钱呢?
what about for cash?
你帮我们拿到钥匙 我们就能拿了这块石头离开地球
You help us get this key, so we can get off this rock--
无意冒犯 爱你的邻居和身边的一切
No offense. Love the neighborhood and all.
然后我可以让你把我卖了
And then I let you sell me.
兰博基尼?
Lambo?
法拉利?
Ferrari?
印地赛车?
Indy?
听着 你拿钱 我走人
Look, you get paid and then I'll split.
所以我要做的就是进去拿钥匙出来是吗?
So all I gotta do is walk in and out?
是的 我们会处理剩下的事
All you gotta do. We'll take care of the rest.
穿越火花 怀揣希望而逝
Cross my spark and hope to die.
我大声说出来的时候觉得很老套
Wow! That was corny when I said it out loud.
那大个子怎么说? 擎天或者别的什么
What about the big man? Optimal, or whatever.
你让我来处理
You let me worry about him.
怎么样?
Cool?
好啦 他加入了 开心 耶!
Ah! Got him! He's in, baby! Whoo!
你们都是能变形汽车的机器人
Y'all are robots that transform into cars,
你们都来自遥远的太空
even though you're from way out in space.
但现在有把钥匙可以打开通往你们家乡之门?
But now there's this key that opens a portal back to your home?
你们知道这些是因为有个灯塔有射线射向天空
Oh, and you know this because there's a beacon light in the sky
而我因为是人类所以看不见
that I can't see because I'm human.
-你说得好像很奇怪似的 -这超怪的好么
You say that like it's weird. It's super weird.
你知道最奇怪的是什么吗? 马克·沃尔伯格要离开时髦乐队了!
You know what's weird? Marky Mark is leaving the Funky Bunch!
-我听说他现在只想追求演艺事业 这太疯狂了! -怎么啦？
- I heard he's just gonna pursue acting now. - That's crazy! What?
为什么会这样……多么美好的世界
How does that... What a world.
无论如何 朋友
Whatever, man.
我只是想赚钱
I'm just trying to collect this money
在你那愤怒的老板发飙之前把他送离地球
and get your angry-ass boss off of Earth before he blows a gasket.
别往心里去
Don't take it personal.
他只是想家
He just misses home.
我觉得他一直为我们被困在这里而自责
And I think he blames himself for us getting stuck here.
地球本该是一个中转站
Earth was supposed to be a pit stop, you know,
一个让我们重新集结然后一起回家参战的地方
a place for us to regroup and rejoin the war back home.
擎天柱觉得我们被困在这里都是他的错
Prime feels like it's his fault we've been stranded here,
就像他要一个人搞定一切一样
like he has to fix it all on his own.
好了 全体注意 前面有保安了
All right, team, heads up. There's security up ahead.
不错!
Nice!
这会很有趣的 伙计
This is gonna be fun, man.
不 不 兄弟 你需要改变一下外形
No, no, no. No, bro. You need to switch it up.
你得变成直升机或者快艇什么的
You need to turn into a helicopter or a speedboat or something.
我有比这更好的东西
I got something way better than that.
有你的
Good call.
我不喜欢这个计划
I do not like this plan.
幻影可不是一个喜欢安分的主
Yeah, Mirage isn't really known for being quiet.
至少幻影是我们中的一员
At least Mirage is one of us.
我们不应该依赖人类
We should not be relying on a human.
他们是我的朋友
They are my friends.
我知道有一个对你很好的人类 大黄蜂
I know one was good to you, Bee,
但这不是我们的世界
but this is not our world.
人类总是会保护属于他们的东西
The humans will always protect what is theirs.
我们只能相信自己的同类
We can only trust our own kind.
你只是接受不了真相!
You can't handle the truth!
我不让你再去汽车影院了
I do not want you going to that drive-in theater anymore.
夜莺 搜索这个岛
Nightbird, search the island.
狩猎终于接近尾声
Finally, the hunt draws to a close.
喂?
Hello?
糖糖
Fudge.
-嘿 你没事吧? -后退！
Hey, are you okay? Back up!
-你还好吗? -后退! 后退! 后退!
Yo, are you okay? Back up! Back up! Back up!
我以为这里没人
I didn't think anyone was in here.
就是这样
That's it.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我 呃…
I'm, uh...
看门的
the janitor.
保安!
Security!
不 不 不! 你没必要这么做! 事情不是你看到的那样
No, no, no! You don't have to do that! It's not what it looks like.
看起来你是想偷博物馆的东西
It looks like you're trying to steal museum property.
好吧 确实看起来有点像那样
Okay, it's a little what it looks like.
哦 我靠
Oh, shit.
嘿 嘿! 哟 哟! 反正这也不是你的
Hey, hey! Hey, hey, yo, yo! It doesn't belong to you anyway.
不 不! 停下来! 别…
No, no, no! Just stop! Just...
嘿 嘿! 放松 放松 听我解释
Hey, hey! Relax, relax, and let me explain.
这东西属于……
It belongs to...
…这些…
...to these...
这些来自太空的巨型机器人
these giant robots from space.
真的吗?
Really?
听着 我需要这个
Look, I'm gonna need that.
该死
Damn!
嘿 嘿 ! 这是怎么回事? 别动
Hey, hey, hey! What's going on here? Don't move.
伙计 你这才出现!
Man, it's about time you showed up!
钥匙
The key.
-你说的是真的 -是的
You were telling the truth. Yeah.
但这几个不是我一伙的
But those ones aren't with me.
杀了他们 把钥匙找来给我
Rip the flesh from their bones and bring me the key.
这是你的了
It's yours.
伙计们 有人跟来了!
Guys, we got company!
汽车人 保护好钥匙!
Autobots, protect the key!
接我这招
Catch!
别跑那么快
Not so fast!
哦 他们现在飞起来了?  这些家伙到底是谁?
Oh, they're flying now? Who the hell are these guys?
这不可能!
Impossible!
我就喜欢看低等生物遇到高等种族
I enjoy that look of confusion
表现出那种困惑不解的表情
when an inferior being meets a higher power.
那些到底是什么鬼?
What the hell are those things?
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
嘿!  别跟着我!  我不是跟着你!
Hey! Stop following me! I'm not following you!
我们只是从同一个方向在逃跑
I'm just escaping in the same direction.
∮ 继续前进 ∮
∮ Were moving on ∮
∮ 要坚强 ∮
∮ Keeping strong ∮
∮ 不管别人怎么想 ∮
∮ Dont you let them Steer you wrong ∮
∮ 跟着节拍 ∮
∮ It,s a groove thang ∮
∮ 得到心中所想 ∮
∮ Gonna give you what you Want ∮
∮ 只有.. ∮
∮ Just as long.. ∮
快跑!
Run!
走 走!
Go, go!
快跑!
Run!
走 走!
Go, go, go, go, go!
小心!
Watch out!
谢谢
Thanks.
天灾 我找到钥匙了
Scourge, I have eyes on the key.
擎天柱 我们快要压不住这些家伙了…
Prime, I don't think we can hold these guys...
哦  不!
Oh, no!
我的上帝! 放我下来!
My God! Put me down!
哇 太吓人了
Whoa, that was so scary.
哦 帅啊 你还活着
Oh, cool. You're still alive.
去拿钥匙!
Get the key!
诺亚 快离开这里!
Noah, get out of here!
放开我! 我讨厌蜘蛛!
Get off me! I hate spiders!
快 快 快! 别死 别死!
Go, go, go! Don't die, don't die, don't die, don't die!
走! 快离开这里!
Go! Get out of here!
这么快就想走?
Leaving so soon?
哟! 当心!
Yo! Look out!
钥匙!
The key!
游戏玩够了 我自己去取
Enough of these games. I'll get it myself.
在我眼皮底下可不行
Not on my watch.
哦 别害怕 人类
Aw, don't be frightened, humans.
这一切很快就会结束
This'll all be over soon.
你自称擎天柱
And you call yourself a Prime.
元始天尊会感到羞愧的
Primus would be ashamed.
我受够了被小东西给挡住去路
I'm tired of little things getting in my way.
大黄蜂!
Bee!
哦 队长! 我的队长!
O Captain! My Captain!
不!
No!
大黄蜂
Bee.
现在我要给我的勋章收藏增加一位领袖金刚
Now to add a Prime to my collection.
巨无霸
Maximals.
好 让我们好好打一架
Good. Maybe we'll get a real fight.
不 我们已经得到了我们想要的
No. We got what we came for.
不
No.
这不可能
This cannot be.
我们现在必须走了 跟我来
We must go now. Come with me.
都我的错 死的那个应该是我
This is my fault. It should've been me.
节哀顺变
I'm sorry for your loss.
无意冒犯 女士 你是谁?
No offense, lady, but who are you again?
我的名字叫飞箭
My name is Airazor.
我是巨无霸
I am a Maximal.
一个来自过去和未来的战士
A warrior from both your past and future.
哦  对 那…那些 懂的
Oh, right. That-- That tracks. Yeah.
我们在母星毁灭之前逃离了那里
We fled our home planet on the eve of its destruction.
我们躲避到了地球 寻求庇护
We sought refuge and hid here on Earth.
这样 所以你们是巨无霸 你们都是汽车人
Right. So you're a Maximal. Y'all are Autobots.
那之前袭击我们的是什么东西?
What was those things that attacked us earlier?
恐惧兽 侍奉黑暗饥饿之神
Terrorcons. Servants of a dark, hungry god
那个以吞噬行星为生
who feeds on entire worlds to sustain himself.
宇宙大帝
Unicron.
你是说这个宇宙大帝吃行星是为了生存?
So you're saying this thing Unicron eats planets to survive?
是的 他给予了他的犬马暗能量
Yes. And he imbues his servants, like Scourge,
好比天灾 让他所向披靡
with dark energy, which makes him all but invincible.
他对宇宙大帝感恩戴德
He is entirely beholden to Unicron.
宇宙大帝由此掌控了天灾的灵魂
Through his power, he possesses Scourge's soul.
醒来吧 我的黑暗主人
Awaken, my dark master.
平身
Rise.
我饿得要命
My hunger is killing me.
你找到了什么?
What have you found?
救赎
Salvation.
银河系将再次成为您的盛宴 我的主人
The galaxy will once again be yours to feast on, my master.
我应该自己去取钥匙的
I should've gotten the key myself.
我早知道不该依赖人类的
I should've known better than to rely on humans.
嘿 等一下 怎么 你在怪我吗?
Yo, hold up. What, you blaming me?
去之前你也没告诉我吸星老怪的事啊
After you conveniently left out the part about a planet-eating monster?
因为你 宇宙大帝现在能用钥匙
Because of you, Unicron will now use the key
毁灭宇宙中的每一个星球
to consume every planet in the universe!
也包括我的母星
Including my home world.
他没有拿到钥匙 至少不是全部
He doesn't have the key. At least not all of it.
蠢蛋
You fool!
-这只是一半的钥匙 -饶命
This is only half the key. Please!
巨无霸……一定是他们把钥匙分成了两把
The Maximals... They must have split it.
借口!
Excuses!
找到另一半钥匙 否则你就得
Complete the key, or else you will wish you had died
和这个星球上的其他人一样都去死
with the rest of your planet.
为了安全起见 我们把钥匙分成了两部分
We broke the key into two pieces for safekeeping,
然后分裂并躲藏起来
then splintered and went into hiding.
我不知道另一半在哪里
I do not know where the other half is.
据我所知 我们最后的族人了
For all I know, I am the last of our kind.
应该在秘鲁
It's in Peru.
你怎么知道的?
How you know that?
是石头上的符号
It's the symbols on the stone.
它们只在世界上的另一个地方被记录下来
They were only ever recorded in one other place in the world.
库斯科的印加太阳神庙
The Inca Temple of the Sun in Cusco.
它是西半球最古老的建筑之一 我...我...
It's one of the oldest buildings in the western hemisphere. I'm-I'm...
我猜这不可能是巧合
I'm guessing that that can't be a coincidence.
如果你能追踪到秘鲁的那些符号 那些怪物也能
If you can track those symbols to Peru, so can the Terrorcons.
我们得赶在他们之前到达那里
We need to get there before they do.
然后干掉天灾 拿到他的部分拼成完整的钥匙
And then kill Scourge and take his piece to complete the key.
等一下 等一下
Yo. Hold up. Hold up.
你想找到另一把钥匙
You want to find this other key
把它送给那个刚揍了你们一顿的家伙
and deliver it to the guy that just kicked your asses.
曲速钥匙是我们回家的唯一途径
The Transwarp Key is our only way home.
如果这家伙得到了那东西 地球就完了!
If this dude gets ahold of that thing, it's game over for Earth!
我们的家人 每个人!
Our families, everybody!
我也去
I'm going.
不可能
Out of the question.
无意冒犯 但我不会把地球托付给一个
No offense, but I'm not trusting my home to a guy
连自己的都保护不了的人
who couldn't even protect his.
地球是我的家 我也要去
This is my planet. I'm going.
你呢?
What about you?
我?  你叫什么名字?
Me? What is your name?
埃琳娜
Elena.
Elena,
你能带我们去神庙吗?
will you lead us to this temple?
阻止世界末日的机会
Chance to stop the end of the world.
实际上
Actually,
你将拯救两个世界的末日
you'll be saving two worlds.
好的
Yeah.
是你吗 刺猬?
Yo, is that you, Sonic?
你怎么起来了 小狐狸?
What are you doing up, Tails?
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
太烫了?
This too hot?
你玩那个游戏玩得太多了
You playing that game too much.
休息一下 这样你的手就可以休息一下
Give it a rest, so your hand can take a break.
我要打败它
I'm gonna beat it.
我赌你赢 兄弟
My money's on you, bro.
我们不会放弃
We don't quit.
来吧 睡一会儿 好吗?
Come on, get some sleep, all right?
嘿 你看
Yo, listen, um,
我得...我得出去一段时间
I gotta-- I gotta head out for a while.
我也不知道什么时候能回来
And I don't know when I'm gonna be back.
为什么?
Why?
哦 我靠
Oh, shit.
什么……不 不 不!
What the... No, no, no!
不! 停下来! 关掉! 关掉!
No! Stop, please! Turn off! Turn off!
你能不能 我告诉过你别动
Yo, won't you-- I told you to sit tight.
关掉它 我不能关掉它 抱歉
Stop it. I can't turn it off. I'm sorry.
那是机器人吗?
Is that a robot?
不 不 回去 回去睡觉
No, no, no. Go-- Go back to bed.
嘿 关掉它! 我觉得你弄坏的线路把我的灯也弄坏了
Yo, shut it off! I think your bad hot-wiring messed up my lights.
我拿球棒 哟 冷静 给我球棒
I got the bat. Yo, chill. Give me that.
-他是说“蝙蝠”吗? -你会弄醒妈妈的!
- Did he say "bat"? - You're gonna wake up Ma!
我就知道你是个机器人
I know you're a robot.
克里斯?
Kris?
哟 你刮花了我的油漆
Yo! You scratched my paint!
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
天啊 他们不是这样对待外星人的
Man, they didn't treat E.T. like this.
你认识这个机器人? 是啊
You know this thing? Yeah.
我们是工作上的朋友
We're just work friends.
“工作上朋友”? 你可进入过我的身体
"Work friends"? You've been inside me.
听着 我告诉你那件我必须去做的事
Look, that thing I told you I have to go do?
这是为了他和他的队员
It's for him and his crew.
我们要阻止世界末日的到来
We're trying to stop the end of the world.
世界末日?
The world's ending?
不! 也许吧 60比40
No! Maybe. Sixty-forty.
你知道我不会让这种事发生的
You know I'm not gonna let that happen.
但这就是我必须离开的原因
But that's why I have to leave.
我去拿点我的装备
I'll go get my things.
好倔的孩子
Tough kid.
怎么啦？不 等等 等等 你不能一起来
What? No. Whoa, whoa. Hold up. Hold up. You're not coming.
-为什么? 你需要有人保护你 -那里太危险了 克里斯
- Why? You need someone to watch your back. - It's too dangerous, Kris.
我需要你留在这里照顾妈妈
And I need you to stay here and take care of Mom.
因为你可能再也不会回来了
'Cause you might not come back.
嘿  机器人
Hey, robot.
-我? -怎么啦?
- Me? - 'Sup?
照顾我哥哥 好吗?
Watch out for my brother. Okay?
没问题 小家伙
You got it, little man.
不 我是认真的
Nah, I'm serious.
如果他受伤了 我会来找你的
If he gets hurt, I'm coming after you.
别担心 我会保护诺亚 我保证
Don't worry. I got Noah's back. I promise.
主队吗?
Home team?
主队
Home team.
这孩子有心
Kid's got heart.
真有勇气
Cojones muy grande.
武当在楼里 宝贝!
Wu-Tang is in the building, baby!
低调
Way to be incognito.
别这样 擎天柱 微笑一下
Aw, come on, Prime. Smile a little bit.
不会疼的 让我看看你的下牙
It won't hurt. Let me see that underbite.
好吧 我们要坐什么喷气机去秘鲁?
All right. So what kind of jet we taking to Peru?
还是一架飞机?哪一个都可以
Or is it a plane? Either one's fine.
我只要头等舱 好吗? 因为我的腿很长
I just need first class, okay? 'Cause I got long-ass legs.
他是一架飞机
Uh, well, he is a plane.
不 不  别啊……
No. No, no. Don't...
别告诉我我们在飞……
Don't tell me we're flying on...
哦 不
Oh, no.
我的小伙子!我是大飞机 天空之王!
My lads! I am Stratosphere, lord of the skies!
是的 我要去秘鲁
Yeah, I'm walking to Peru.
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my gosh.
对不起
Sorry.
我紧张的时候就唱歌 那能让我平静下来
I sing when I get nervous. It usually calms me down.
第一次坐飞机?
First time flying?
伙计 这是我第一次离开纽约
Man, this is my first time leaving New York.
我的天啊 哦 上帝
Oh, my God. Oh, God.
布朗克斯 是吧?
So the Bronx, huh?
布鲁克林 好吗?
Brooklyn, all right?
一直在纽约东部
East New York all day.
我来自布什维克
I'm from Bushwick.
真的吗?
Really?
我和我爸 我们以前常去
Um, me and my dad, we used to go to this--
尼克博克街和格林街的披萨店
this pizza spot down on Knickerbocker and Greene.
托尼的披萨吗? 喔
Tony's Pizza? Wow.
跟我说说你爸爸吧
So, uh, tell me about him, your pops.
他是个什么样的人?
What-- What was he like?
他做了40年的出租车司机
He was a-- He was a cabbie for 40 years.
你见过的最聪明的人
Smartest guy you ever met.
他什么都可以跟你聊
He could talk to you about anything.
历史 科学 板球
History, science, cricket.
板球?
Cricket?
而且他也没上过大学
And he ain't never even go to college either.
他以前总是说
He used to always say,
“如果你愿意去观察 愿意去倾听
"If you keep your eyes and your ears open,
生活会告诉你一切你想知道的 ”
life will show you everything you need to know."
所以你才答应了去
So that's why you said yes to all of this.
我想如果他在某处看着我
I figured if he is somewhere watching,
然后看到他的女儿做出如此疯狂的事
then seeing his daughter do something crazy like this
肯定会让他感到骄傲
would definitely make him proud.
你真的认为钥匙会在秘鲁吗?
You really think this key thing's in Peru?
我....我想是的
I-- I think so.
所有的证据都指向那里
The evidence lines up.
如果是的话 而且我们拿到了
Well, if it is, and we get our hands on it,
那我们就得毁了它
then we gotta destroy it.
怎么啦？
What?
没有这两个零件 他们无法把钥匙连在一起
They can't unite the key without both pieces.
没有那把钥匙 就不会有宇宙大帝 地球也不会被吃掉
No key, no Unicron, no Earth getting eaten.
是啊 但那样他们就回不了家了
Yeah, but then they can't get home.
我们得为自己着想
We gotta think about us.
你要做的就是找到它
Look, all you gotta do is find it.
剩下的我来处理
And I'll take care of the rest.
你觉得能量块能让他起死回生吗?
Do you think an Energon infusion could bring him back?
也许吧
Perhaps.
如果我们能把他带回塞伯坦
If we could get him back to Cybertron.
我不该带我们离开家这么远
I never should have taken us so far from home.
哇! 千斤顶得把动力转向装置修好
Wow! Wheeljack needs to fix that power steering.
对不起 我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
我在享受一个在蝴蝶和毛毛虫之间的
I was taking in a harmonious moment
和谐而宁静的时刻
between a serene butterfly and an unruffled caterpillar.
这样的宁静
Such tranquility.
嘿 老人家 你从哪里来? 塞伯坦
Yo-ho-ho. Oye, papo, where you from? Cybertron.
你从哪学来的口音? 口音吗? 什么口音?
So where'd you get that accent? Accent? What accent?
你知道我在说什么吗? 我只是觉得这很酷
You know what I'm saying? I'm just saying it's cool.
我正想说 “你 米拉 爸爸 ?”
I was about to be like, "¿Yo, mira, papi, de dónde eres?"
佩罗 我不想假设你也说西班牙语
Pero I didn't want to assume that you speak Spanish too,
因为这样……对吧?
because then... Right?
有点种族歧视啊 兄弟
A little racist, hermano.
我不是想 你知道…哟
I'm not trying to be, you know... Yo.
但无论如何……的使命 跟我来
But anyway... The mission. Follow me.
但他是个机器人 所以
But he's a robot, like, so,
这怎么算是种族歧视?
how's that racist?
好了 伙计们 看看这个
Okay, you guys, check this out.
你给我的坐标是一座老教堂
The coordinates you gave me correspond to an old church.
看一看
Take a look.
那是圣多明各 西班牙人把它建在一座古老的印加神庙上
That's Santo Domingo. The Spanish built it on top of an old Inca temple.
正确 我在院子里测到了一些残余能量读数
Correcto. I picked up some residual energy readings around the courtyard,
所以我猜钥匙就在附近
so I'm guessing the key's somewhere close by.
但我们可能会遇到一些麻烦
But we may have some trouble getting there.
印加太阳神
Inti Raymi.
这是一个让整个城市暂停的节日
It's a festival that shuts down the whole city.
看来是夜间任务了 不行
Guess it's a night mission then. No.
天灾可能已经在来的路上了
Scourge could already be here.
我们必须赶在他之前找回另一半钥匙
We must retrieve the other half before he does.
我和埃琳娜会去找?
Me and Elena will do it. Hmm?
你们连两个街区都走不到
Y'all would never make it two blocks.
教堂周围都有安保人员 你不可能穿过去的
There's human security all around the church. You'll never get through.
那我们就得从你的书里拿出一个剧本来
Then we'll have to take a play out of your book.
我们会在众目睽睽之下
We'll hide in plain sight.
混入游行队伍中
We'll blend in with the parade.
这主意不错
It is not a bad idea.
我们会留意那些怪物的
We will keep an eye out for the Terrorcons.
一有麻烦的迹象 我们就进去
On first sign of trouble, we are going in.
诺亚 快想想
Yo, Noah, think fast.
如果你需要帮助 就喊一声
And if you need help, just holler.
我马上就位
I am in position.
好了 安全了
All right, coast is clear.
诺亚 埃琳娜 该走了
Noah, Elena, it's go time.
融入他们 表现自然
Blend in. Act natural.
汽车人肯定在用他们的新宠物
Autobots must be using their new pets
到寺庙去
to reach the temple.
可爱
Lovely.
他们在为我们做我们的工作
They're doing our work for us.
去取回来
Go fetch.
钥匙肯定在这里的某个地方
The key's gotta be in here somewhere.
是的
Yeah.
那件石雕是17世纪的
That stonework is 17th century.
我们要找的东西
What we're looking for is something
可老得多
much, much older.
这是什么?和飞箭的徽章一样
What is it? It's the same insignia on Airazor.
但是方向不对
But it's not lined up right.
等等 你看到了吗?
Wait, you see that?
我觉得这下面有东西
I think there's something under here.
还有一个
There's another one.
这个
There is.
现在做什么?
Now what?
我以为它会...
I thought it would've--
那是印第安纳琼斯式那种东西
That's some Indiana Jones-type shit.
你确定吗?
You sure about this?
不
No.
发现天灾了吗?
Any sign of Scourge?
没有 这里没问题
Nope, all clear here.
嗯 是的
Uh, yeah.
这里都是些游行聚会的人
It's just groupies over here.
继续观察 幻影
Stay on task, Mirage.
擎天柱 你得学会放松 伙计
Prime, you gotta learn how to relax, my man.
你知道 我们肯定是五千年来第一批来到这里的人
You know, we must be the first people to walk here in half a millennium.
哟 刺猬 你死了吗?
Yo, Sonic. You dead yet?
不
No.
等等 你刚才叫我刺猬吗?
Wait, did you just call me Sonic?
我想那是座寺庙
I think that's a temple.
我们在找什么?
What are we looking for?
看到神庙上的符号了吗?
You see the symbols on that temple?
和院子里的一模一样
They match the ones in the courtyard.
我想应该在上面
I think it's up there.
我想我们找到了来这里的目的了
I think we found what we came here for.
我一直想知道那是什么感觉
I always wondered what it would feel like
亲眼目睹文物被发现
to be there when artifacts were actually found.
好吧 来吧 用力
All right. Now come on, push.
你在推吗?
Are you even pushing?
是的 我在推
Yeah, I'm pushing.
等等 什么? 让我想想
Wait, what? Just-- Just let me think.
哦 不 不 它在哪里?
Oh, no, no. Where is it?
有时候 就像 就像假底层之类的
Sometimes there's, like, a-- like a false bottom or something.
看
Look.
我想我有发现了 看到这些符号了吗?
I think I found something. You see these symbols?
我见过这样的标记 我博物馆里的艾拉梭雕像
I've seen markings like this-- the Airazor statue at my museum.
他们是新的
They're new.
他们不在曲速钥匙上
They're not on the Transwarp Key.
有两个
There's two of them.
幻影?
Mirage?
让我们继续 给我一点时间
Let's keep moving. Just give me a second.
快跑!
Run!
快 快!
Go, go, go, go, go!
幻影! 我们有麻烦了!
Mirage! We got trouble!
有个怪物在下面! 你们在哪儿?
One of those things is down here! Where are you guys?
撑住! 我来了
Hang tight! I'm on the way.
汽车人在移动
The Autobots are moving.
他们一定找到了钥匙
They must have found the key.
来吧!
Come on!
飞箭 人类在哪里?
Airazor, where are the humans?
他们在地下 往丛林里去了
They're underground, heading towards the jungle.
伙计 他们在跟踪我们!
Aw, man, they're tailing us!
做点什么! 你想让我怎么做?
Do something! What do you want me to do?
你一直都带着枪吗?
You had a gun this whole time?
擎天柱 你在搞什么鬼?
Prime, what the hell are you doing?
我要拿回天灾的钥匙
I'm going to take back Scourge's key
然后取下他的脑袋
and then take off his head.
伙计们! 我需要一点帮助!
Guys! I could use a little help!
是有人请求支援吗?
Did someone call for backup?
刹车 刹车 刹车! 怎么啦？
Brake, brake, brake! What?
刹车!
Brake!
这是替大黄蜂的!
This is for Bee!
到这里来
Come here.
坚持住!
Hold on!
我喜欢你的火气 擎天柱
I love your fire, Prime.
但你会死的像尘埃
But you're going to die on this speck of dust.
我想不出更好的地方来埋葬你
I can think of no better place to bury you.
我要杀了你 天灾
I will end you, Scourge.
这是一个承诺
That is a promise.
他们逃走了
They're getting away.
这次不会了
Not this time.
我听到水的声音
I hear water.
我们在哪里?
Where are we?
那是什么?
What was that?
你是谁?
Who are you?
你为什么要找钥匙?
And why are you hunting for the key?
哟 大金刚! 离我的朋友远点!
Yo, Donkey Kong! Stay away from my friends!
幻影?  别担心 你兄弟会处理好的
Uh, Mirage? Don't worry. Your boy's got this.
陌生人危险! 陌生人危险!
Stranger danger! Stranger danger!
嘿 嘿!
Hey, hey, hey!
嘿! 这里 小猫猫
Hey! Over here, kitty, kitty.
放下武器!
Stand down!
我不会再问第二次了
I won't ask a second time.
不! 你们都停下来!
No! All of you, stop!
飞箭 擎天圣
Airazor. Primal.
我以为你们都牺牲了 你们所有人
I thought you were lost. All of you.
其他的人呢……他们是否……
The others... Are they...
我是唯一活下来的
I am all that is left.
擎天柱 这些是我巨无霸同伴
Prime, these are my fellow Maximals.
犀牛勇士
Rhinox.
黄豹
Cheetor.
抱歉 吓到你了 兄弟
Sorry about scaring you, brother.
害怕吗? 拜托
Scared? Please.
我才没害怕
I'm not scared.
那只是机油
That's just engine oil.
还有我们的领袖 擎天圣
And our leader, Optimus Primal.
擎天圣吗?
Optimus Primal?
以你的名字命名 塞伯坦的传奇战士
Named after you, the legendary warrior of Cybertron.
这是我的荣幸
It's an honor.
飞箭 很高兴见到你 老朋友
Airazor, I'm happy to see you, old friend.
但把其他人带到这里并不是我们的计划
But bringing others here was not part of our plan.
恐怕你带来了坏消息
I fear you bring dark tidings.
天灾已经来到地球
Scourge has come to Earth.
他找到我们了
He's found us.
他有一半的钥匙
And he has half of the key.
我们必须赶在他之前找到另外一半
We must find the second piece before he does.
但它不在洞里
But it wasn't in the cave.
这是 但为了安全起见 我们很久以前就搬走了
It was. But we moved it long ago to keep it safe.
它现在在哪里?
Where is it now?
跟我来
Come with me.
看起来不是很好
That doesn't look so good.
天灾袭击你的时候 他会留下印记
When Scourge touches you, he leaves a mark.
但我会没事的
But I'll be all right.
刚才你叫我刺猬
Hey, back there you called me Sonic.
是的 你弟弟得了病
Yeah. Your little bro's got this thing
在广播中使用真名 所以…
about using real names over the airwaves, so...
等等 你跟克里斯谈过了? 啊哈
Wait, you been talking to Kris? Uh-huh.
他给我这个 为了联系你
He gave me this to keep tabs on you,
确保我遵守我的诺言
make sure I'm keeping my promise.
哦  在这里
Oh, here.
下次 附上警告标签
Next time, include warning labels.
不用了 留着吧
Nah, go ahead, keep it.
我想我穿起来确实更好看
I guess it does look better on me.
别问我身体的哪个部位
Just don't ask what part of my body it came from.
那么 你是谁?
So, who are you?
我们巨无霸是一个先进的种族
We Maximals are an advanced race
致力于宇宙中生命的扩张
dedicated to the expansion of life throughout the universe.
我们用超曲之钥寻找新的世界
We use the Transwarp Key to visit young worlds.
纳斯卡线条 蒂卡尔神庙
The Nazca Lines, the Temple at Tikal--
是你们留下的 对吗?
That was you guys, right?
不是我们
Not us.
我们不能为人类的聪明才智而邀功
We cannot claim credit for human ingenuity.
但你有钥匙 为什么要留在这个世界上?
But you had the key. Why stay on this world?
当宇宙大帝毁灭了我们的世界
When Unicron destroyed our world,
我们发誓要不计代价
we took an oath dedicated to the preservation of life,
保护生灵
no matter the cost.
而地球是一个安全的避难所
And Earth has been a safe refuge.
我是阿玛鲁
This is Amaru.
他和他的家人是一个部落最后的后代
He and his family are the last descendants of a tribe
他们已经守护了我们几百年
that has watched over us for hundreds of years.
当我们到达时 他们和我们分享了他们的世界
When we arrived, they shared their world with us.
我们一起保护了他们的子民
And together we protected its people
还有我们的秘密
and our secret.
你和人类结盟了
You allied with humans.
是的
We did.
如果你把钥匙给我们
If you give us this key,
明天我会点燃灯塔 把天灾吸引来
tomorrow I will light the beacon and bring Scourge to us.
巨无霸已经牺牲了自己的行星来保护宇宙
The Maximals have already sacrificed one home to protect the universe.
我不会再冒失去另一个星球的风险
I won't risk losing another.
作为领导者 我相信你能理解
As a leader, I know you understand.
他不是我想象中的擎天柱
He is not the Optimus Prime I imagined.
他失去的太多了
Well, he has lost so much.
如果钥匙落入坏人之手
Many more will perish
那会有更多的人死去
if the key falls into the wrong hands.
如果你还有机会拯救我们的家
If you had another chance to save our home,
你会有不同的选择吗?
would you act any differently?
擎天柱 你来 我想给你看样东西
Optimus, come. I want to show you something.
你的朋友会在这里找到安宁
Your friend will find peace here.
这是能量块
This is raw Energon.
这个山谷里盛产它
The valley is rich with it.
这能让大黄蜂复活吗?
Could this revive Bee?
抱歉 但在这种状态下 它是惰性的
I'm sorry, but in this state, it is inert.
需要很大的能量才能点燃它
It would take a great power to ignite it.
比我们这里的任何能量都巨大
Greater than anything we have here.
我看你很惊讶我们把钥匙交给他们
I see that you are surprised we entrust the key to them.
是的
Yes, I am.
我和他们在一起很久了
I've been amongst them a long time now.
它们比表面上看到的要复杂得多
There is more to them than meets the eye.
它们值得保存
They are worth saving.
如果我们不摧毁它呢?
What if we didn't destroy it?
也许还有别的办法能保住我们俩的家
Maybe there's another way to-- to save both our homes.
埃琳娜 我这辈子犯了很多错
Elena, I made a lot of mistakes in my life.
这是不同的
This is different.
我不能失败
I can't fail at this.
我不能让我的家人失望
I can't let my family down.
你就像他一样 你知道吗?
You're just like him. You know that?
谁?
Who?
擎天柱
Optimus.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
他也感觉到了 感觉什么?
He feels it too. Feels what?
像一头负重的野兽
Like a beast of burden
只是想把整个世界的重担扛在肩上
just trying to carry the weight of the world on his shoulders.
你以为他是在发号施令
You think he's some-- some general barking orders,
但当我看着他
but when I look at him,
我只看到一个大哥哥想要保护他的家人
all I see is a big brother trying to protect his family.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
飞箭吗?
Airazor?
我能感觉到天灾!
I can feel Scourge!
他是……在我心里
He's... ...in my mind.
快跑 埃琳娜!
Run, Elena!
不!
No!
飞箭
Airazor.
他们找到我们了
They found us.
所有人 防守就位!
Everyone, defensive positions!
诺亚 保护好钥匙
Noah, guard the key.
带上埃琳娜 找个安全的地方躲起来
Take Elena and find someplace safe to hide.
我们必须保护人类
We must protect the humans.
想我了吗?
Miss me?
诺亚 埃琳娜 快出去!
Noah, Elena, get out of here!
我们必须摧毁它
We have to destroy it.
诺亚!
Noah!
不!
No!
不要
Don't.
我知道你想保护你的人
I know you want to protect your people,
但如果你毁了钥匙
but if you destroy that key,
我们将永远失去家园
our home will be lost forever.
我们无法选择
We do not have to choose.
拜托 诺亚
Please, Noah.
埃琳娜!
Elena!
快走!
Go!
埃琳娜!
Elena!
等等 等等  我不是已经杀了你吗?
Wait, wait. Didn't I kill you already?
不!
No!
我是能把你剁成肉酱的巨无霸
I'm the Maximal that's going to rip out your spark.
我们走着瞧吧
We'll see about that.
杀了他们!
Kill them!
飞箭 不!
Airazor, no!
我控制不住……
I can't hold it back...
…太长时间了
...much longer.
打吧 飞箭
Fight it, Airazor.
记住我们的誓言 擎天圣
Remember our oath, Primal.
不计代价
No matter the cost.
我不行了! 飞箭 不!
I can't hold it back! Airazor, no!
擎天圣!
Primal!
没关系
It's okay.
动手
Do it.
擎天圣
Primal.
不计代价
No matter the cost.
埃琳娜! 埃琳娜 看着我
Elena! Elena, look at me.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
天灾拿到钥匙了
Scourge has the key.
觉醒吧 全能的宇宙大帝 你的时代来临了
Awaken, almighty Unicron. Your time has come.
对不起 诺亚
I am sorry, Noah.
你是在为自己着想
You were looking out for your own.
我都不能为此生你的气
I can't even be angry at you for that.
在我的母星 我们相信与黑暗的战斗将会继续
On my home world, we believe that the battle with darkness will continue
直到合而为一
till all are one.
我忘记了这一点
I lost sight of that.
你为你的而战 正如我为我的而战
You fought for yours as I fought for mine
我们本该一起对抗黑暗的
when we should have been fighting the darkness together.
我还没打完呢
Well, I ain't done fighting yet.
好了 大家集合!
All right, everybody, squad up!
把它拿进来
Bring it in.
一定有办法阻止这家伙的
There's got to be a way to stop this dude.
太迟了 超曲速已经启动了
It's too late. The Transwarp has already been activated.
它比超新星拥有更多的能量
It has more energy than a supernova.
任何干扰都会像炸弹一样引爆它
Any interruption will ignite it like a bomb.
唯一能阻止这一切的方法
The only way to stop this process
是很久以前安装的安全密码
is an access code installed long ago as a safeguard.
好吧 那密码是什么?
Okay, what's the code then?
密码和钥匙一起被拆开了
The code was split along with the key.
可悲的是 代码的后半部分随着飞箭一起消失了
Sadly, the second half of that code died with Airazor.
不 等等 等等 我明白了
No, wait, wait, wait. I got it.
把她那一半钥匙藏起来的那个
The one hiding her half of the key--
上面有标记
that had markings in it
就像我在你藏枪的山洞里找到的一样
just like the ones I found in the cave where you hid yours.
它们必须一起完成访问代码
Together, they must complete the access code.
所以我们现在有机会了 对吧?
So we got a chance now, right?
机会渺茫
A slim chance.
这就是我们所需要的
That is all we need
如果你能给我们指路的话 擎天圣
if you will show us the way, Primal.
好吧 我们需要迅速行动
All right. We need to move quickly.
在传送门打开之前我们还有一小段时间
We have a small window before the portal opens
大到足以让宇宙大帝进入
large enough for Unicron to enter.
这座桥由一系列通道环绕
The bridge is girded by a series of tunnels.
它们对于巨无霸来说太小了 但是……
They are too small for Maximals, but...
但对人类来说可以
But not for humans.
如果诺亚和埃琳娜到达中央天线
If Noah and Elena reach the central antenna,
他们可以用密码关闭它
they can use the code to shut it down,
移除跨曲钥匙…
remove the Transwarp Key...
…在宇宙大帝进入大气层之前关闭传送门
...and close the portal before Unicron enters our atmosphere.
但天灾会看到我们的一举一动
But Scourge will be watching our every move.
他会不择手段阻止我们拿到钥匙
He'll do anything to stop us from getting the key.
那我们就和他决斗
Then we bring the fight to him.
汽车人和巨无霸
Autobots and Maximals
一起给桥充电吧
will charge the bridge together
引诱天灾来到战场
and lure Scourge onto the battlefield.
我和埃琳娜从后门溜进去
While me and Elena sneak in through the back way.
听起来我们都要死了
It sounds like we're all going to die.
如果我们要死 那我们就死在战斗中
If we are to die, then we will die fighting
万众一心
all as one.
这个世界是你的 主人
This world is yours, master.
天灾
Scourge,
他们回来了
they're back.
擎天柱
Prime.
保护好钥匙 别让他们接近桥
Protect the key. Don't let them get to the bridge.
巨无霸!
Maximals!
汽车人!
Autobots!
出发!
Roll out!
犀牛勇士 黄豹 变形
Rhinox, Cheetor, maximize!
至少步兵们上钩了
At least the foot soldiers took the bait.
是的 但是天灾没有 他还在守着钥匙
Yeah, but Scourge didn't. He's guarding the key.
好吧 这将引导到曲速控制面板的底部
All right. This should lead to the bottom of the Transwarp control panel.
拿上钥匙 赶紧离开那里 你要怎么做?
Get the key, get the hell out of there. What are you gonna do?
我去分散天灾的注意力
I'm gonna go distract Scourge.
不 你不能单独对付天灾
No, you can't take on Scourge alone.
放松 我是幻影 记得吗?
Relax. I'm Mirage, remember?
一 二 三!
One, two, three!
它在那儿!
Whoomp! There it is! Pow!
我们得快点了
We gotta hurry up.
注意隐蔽!
Take cover!
谁来给我一场真正的战斗!
Someone give me a real fight!
你想要找人战斗? 我来陪你
It's a fight you want? You got one.
他是我的
He was mine.
不!
Nope!
别管我!
Missed me!
诺亚 去拿钥匙
Noah, get to the key.
幻影!
Mirage!
这是什么?
What do we have here?
埃琳娜 走吧!
Elena, go!
勇敢 但徒劳
Brave, but futile.
嘿! 别碰我兄弟!
Hey! Don't mess with my boy!
幻影
Mirage.
没人会记得这个可怜的星球
No one will remember this pathetic planet.
没有人会记得你
And no one will remember you.
幻影 你在干什么?
Mirage, what are you doing?
遵守我的诺言
Keeping my promise.
幻影 不! 快点 你得起来!
Mirage, no! Come on, you gotta get up!
没事的 诺亚
It's okay, Noah.
主场...主队
Home-- Home team.
主队
Home team.
幻影!
Mirage!
幻影?
Mirage?
幻影
Mirage.
杀了另一个人类
Kill the other human.
宇宙大帝
Unicron.
你战斗得很勇敢
You fought bravely.
但这个世界已经是我的了
But this world is already mine.
我们来晚了
We're too late.
嘿!看！
Hey! Look!
嘿 指关节
Hey, Knuckles.
你在吗?
You there? Over.
哟 刺猬
Yo, Sonic.
克里斯!诺亚?
Kris! Noah?
这是怎么呢
What's going on?
幻影在哪儿?
Where's Mirage?
他 他死了
He-- He's gone.
死了?
Gone?
不
No.
对不起 克里斯
I'm sorry, Kris.
我不会赢了
I'm not gonna win this one.
但你不会输 对吧?
But you don't lose, right?
我也不希望
I wish that were true,
但我做不到
but I can't.
不 你可以
Yes, you can.
不行
No.
不行 伙计 我不是你
No, man, I'm not you.
我讨厌生病
I hate being sick.
每当我想要放弃
Whenever I wanna give up,
你总是在旁边告诉我要继续
you're always there telling me to keep going.
但现在轮到我了
But now it's my turn.
继续 诺亚
Keep going, Noah.
你以为你是个无名小卒 但你是我认识的最强壮的人
You think you're a nobody, but you're the strongest guy I know.
你们太可爱了
You guys are so cute.
幻影?
Mirage?
你活了!
You're alive!
嗯 是的 但是…我需要你来开车
Uh, yeah, but... I'm gonna need you to take the wheel.
你能做到的
You can do this.
因为你是我的兄弟
'Cause you're my brother.
纽约 布鲁克林威尔逊大道
Noah Diaz from Wilson Avenue,
公寓2-C的诺亚·迪亚兹
Apartment 2-C, Brooklyn, New York.
电波里不要说真名
No names over the airwaves.
算了吧
Forget that.
让他们知道你是谁
Let 'em know who you are.
天灾!
Yo, Scourge!
还记得我吗?
Remember me?
你觉得你一个人能搞定我?
You think you can take me on alone?
他不是一个人
He is not alone.
我再也不会离开布鲁克林了
I'm never leaving Brooklyn again.
啊! 能量块
Ah! Energon.
擎天柱 !
Prime!
诺亚!
Noah!
我真的受够你们人类了
I'm getting really tired of you humans.
你又来了 你本该死了!
You again. You should've stayed dead!
我是来揍你的
I have come here to kick ass.
很高兴你回来了
Glad to have you back.
大家都守住桥!
Everyone guard the bridge!
埃琳娜 关掉它!
Elena, shut it down!
我们得给她点掩护!
We gotta give her some cover!
我们会扫清道路的
We'll clear the way.
我说的就是这个
That's what I'm talkin' about.
输入访问码 这能有多难?
Punch in an access code... How hard could that be?
哦 你在开玩笑吧
Oh, you've gotta be kidding me.
只有你和我 天灾
Just you and me, Scourge.
让我们彻底做个了结
Let's end this once and for all.
主人 援军来了!
Master, the reinforcements!
好吧 我来搞定
All right, I got this.
我们走吧 小大黄蜂!
Let's go, Bee!
向我的小朋友问好!
Say hello to my little friend!
我们得快点了!
We gotta hurry!
最后一个
Last one.
去死吧 你这个丑陋的母亲
Die, you ugly mother--
你永远不会看到宇宙大帝统治这个世界
You will never see Unicron take this world.
你做到了!
You did it!
布鲁克林 宝贝!
Brooklyn, baby!
不!
No!
宇宙大帝必胜!
Unicron will prevail!
埃琳娜!
Elena!
我受够了!
I've had enough!
是时候向你展示擎天柱的真正力量了!
Time to show you the real power of the Prime!
这是我一个朋友的!
This belongs to a friend of mine!
面板
The panel,
被打坏了
it's destroyed.
我无法停下它
I can't stop it.
汽车人 巨无霸
Autobots, Maximals,
撤退到安全的地方
retreat to safety.
我会亲手毁掉钥匙
I will destroy the key myself.
擎天柱 !不!
Prime! No!
肯定还有别的办法
There's gotta be another way.
大黄蜂 保护他们
Bee, protect them.
你的牺牲成为我们的誓言
Your sacrifice becomes our oath.
谢谢你们 我的朋友们
Thank you, my friends.
大黄蜂!
Bee!
我们不能丢下他!
We can't leave him!
大家跟我来!
Everyone, on me!
住手 擎天柱
Don't, Prime.
你想要什么我都能给你
I can give you everything you want.
去死吧
Then die.
诺亚
Noah.
抓到你了!
I got you!
放开我 诺亚 救你自己
Let me go, Noah. Save yourself.
万众一心
Till all are one.
加大马力 擎天柱
Punch it, Prime.
太好了 宝贝!
Yeah, baby!
宇宙大帝……他死了吗?
Unicron... Is he dead?
被困住了 但没死
Trapped, but not dead.
邪恶永远不可能被完全征服
Evil can never be vanquished completely.
他还可能回来
He could return.
让他来吧
Let him come.
联合起来 我们将摧毁他
United, we will destroy him,
彻彻底底
once and for all.
我是擎天柱
I am Optimus Prime,
汽车人的领袖
leader of the Autobots.
我们失去了曲速钥匙
We have lost the Transwarp Key
有了它我们就能回家
and with it our ability to go home.
但我们收获了一个盟友
But we have gained an ally
在我们与邪恶的战斗中
in our battle against the forces of evil.
它的力量是如此强大
Forces too powerful
单独个体无法击败它
for any of us to defeat on our own.
但只要我们团结 就有机会战胜它
But together, we might just have a chance.
我是诺亚·迪亚兹
I am Noah Diaz.
想知道关于我的什么？
What is there to know about me?
在布鲁克林长大
I was raised out in Brooklyn.
我有个叫我刺猬的弟弟
I got a little bro who calls me Sonic.
如果要拯救宇宙才能拯救我爱的人
And if I gotta help save the universe in order to save the people I love,
好吧 那我会去做
well, then that's what I'm gonna do.
先生 你好吗?
How you doing, sir?
我是来参加工作面试的?
Um, I'm here for the job interview?
诺亚·迪亚兹
Noah Diaz.
我会告诉他们你来了
I'll tell 'em you're here.
本周日的《60分钟》
This Sunday on 60 Minutes,
我坐下来和埃琳娜·华莱士谈话
I sit down to talk with Elena Wallace.
她最近发现了一座地下寺庙 里面有许多地下墓穴
She recently discovered an underground temple with a network of catacombs...
…可以追溯到公元前5000年
...dating back to 5000 BC.
我从没想过会有如此重大的发现
I never could've imagined making a discovery of this significance.
所以这绝对是梦想成真
So it's definitely a dream come true.
布鲁克林 宝贝
Brooklyn, baby.
他们准备好了
They're ready for you.
谢谢 先生 电梯在后面
Thank you, sir. Elevator in the back.
跟我说说你的优势吧?
Why don't you tell me about your strengths?
除了我在电子方面的经验
In addition to my experience with electronics,
我也一直在培养我的团队建设技能
I've also been really developing my team-building skills too.
是这样吗?
Is that so?
听着 我跟你说实话
Look, I'm gonna be honest with you.
你的简历有点单薄
Résumé's a little thin.
是啊 我最近刚找到一份工作
Yeah, well, I just recently had a job
国际性的工作
working internationally.
哦 在哪里……
Oh, was that...
没有 我想你没写在上面
No, I don't think it's on here.
是的……那是一份短期合同
No, it was... it was a short-term contract.
哦 好吧 不错
Oh, well, that's cool.
你为什么不跟我说说呢?
Why don't you tell me about that?
那是在南美洲 所以我得努力学习我的西班牙语
It was in South America. So I got to work on my Spanish.
我妈妈对此非常高兴
My mom was real happy about that.
你知道我在说什么吗? 你知道妈妈的
You know what I'm saying? You know moms.
她真的 但我在外面的时候 说实话 伙计
She's just really-- But while I was out there, honestly, man,
就像工作 工作 工作 你知道吗?
it was really just like work, work, work, you know?
啊 真遗憾 因为我听说秘鲁的食物非常好吃
Ah. That's a shame, because I hear the food is really good in Peru.
等等 我没提秘鲁的事
Wait, I didn't-- I didn't mention anything about Peru.
那就是你去的地方 对吧?
Well, that's where you were, right?
我在库斯科?
I was-- Down in Cusco?
和你还有埃琳娜一起
With you and, uh, Elena
你的 嗯
and your, um,
我不知道 叫他们朋友?
I don't know, call 'em friends?
什么……
What...
这是怎么回事?
What's going on in here?
我们很了解你 迪亚兹先生
We know a lot about you, Mr. Diaz.
你是谁? 中央情报局或者联邦调查局什么的…
Who are you? The CIA or FBI or...
我们是一个秘密的政府组织
We are a secret government organization.
严格保密的那种
Strictly off the books.
我们专门研究全球威胁
We specialize in global threats.
预防星球毁灭之类的
Planetary loss prevention, that kind of thing.
我们正处于一场持续的战争中
We're in the middle of an ongoing war,
我们希望你能加入我们的战斗
and we'd love to have you join the fight.
你和你的团队
You and your whole team.
你知道的
You know,
那些大家伙
the big guys.
不知道你在说什么
No idea what you're talking about.
这是个好答案
That's a good answer.
好吧
All right.
不管怎样 我想让你知道
Either way, I want you to know,
代表国家的感谢
in lieu of the thanks of a grateful nation,
我们会照顾好你弟弟克里斯的健康
we will be taking care of your brother Kris's health care.
所有的医疗
All of it.
从现在开始 他可以全天候接受就医
From now on, he will have 24/7 access
都是世界上顶尖的医生
to the greatest doctors in the world.
这些医生也不会询问病人的账户余额
And these are doctors who don't ask their patients about account balances.
你是认真的吗?
Are you serious?
你拯救了世界 孩子 这是我们最起码能做的
You saved the world, kid. It's the least we can do.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
我们会尽力的
We'll work on that.
你弟弟会好起来的
Your brother's gonna be just fine.
顺便说一句 克里斯说的对
Kris was right, by the way.
电波里不要讲真名
No names over the airwaves.
我们真的需要你这样的人 诺亚
We could really use someone like you, Noah.
你为什么不考虑一下呢?
Why don't you think about it?
“特种部队”?
"G.I. Joe"?
来吧 宝贝 给我看看 给我看看
Come on, baby, show me some. Show me some.
应该可以了
That oughta do it.
这个吗?
This?
这完全是在浪费你的技能和我的专业知识
This is a complete waste of your skills and my expertise.
我觉得结果还不错
Think it came out pretty good.
我想我们可以称之为现代艺术
Well, I guess we could call it modern art
然后卖给苏荷区的几只猫
and sell it to some cats in SoHo.
不 我不卖
Nah, I'm not selling.
怎么啦？
What?
为什么?
Why?
是关于5-0的事吗?
Is this about the 5-0 thing?
不 我告诉过你 我没有抛弃你!
No. I told you, I did not ditch you!
我是在跑闪送 我以为你知道这出戏!
I was running the give-and-go. I thought you knew the play!
好吧 就算我甩了你 即使我没有
All right, let's say I did ditch you, even though I didn't.
看在你的份上 我看到你的脸了 就当我看到了吧
For your sake-- I see your face-- let's just say I did.
看在所有的血 汗和死去的总统份上
I think all the blood, sweat and dead presidents
我为你买这些汽车零件花了很多钱 我们扯平了
I put into getting these car parts for you make us even steven.
不是那样的
It's not that.
这辆车很特别
This car is special.
这辆车是用汽车废件拼的吧!
This car is a jigsaw puzzle made of garbage!
嘿 我打赌这车根本就开不了
Hey, I bet the joint don't even start.
打赌?
Bet?
哟 幻影
Yo, Mirage.
是啊! 你的兄弟来了!
Yeah! Your boy is back!
这家伙说我根本不可能发动!
This dude said I wasn't even gonna start!